In addition to reading in data from files,
除了读取文件中的数据之外
we can actually import Python code from other scripts.
我们还可以导入其他脚本中的 Python 代码
This is especially helpful if you're working on a bigger project where you want to
如果你处理的是大型项目 希望将代码整理成多个文件
organize your code into multiple files and reuse code in those files.
并重复利用这些文件中的代码 则能够导入其他脚本中的 Python 代码会非常方便
If the Python script you want to import is in the same directory as your current script,
如果你要导入的 Python 脚本与当前脚本位于同一个目录中
you just type import,
只需输入 import
followed by the name of the file without the dot PY extension.
然后输入文件名 无需添加 .py 扩展名
Imports statements are written at the top of a Python script,
导入语句写在 Python 脚本的顶部
each one on a separate line.
每个导入语句各占一行
Python will still run if imports statements are included later in the script,
如果将导入语句放在脚本的后面 Python 依然会运行
but it's common practice to always have these at the top.
但是常规做法是始终将这些导入语句放在顶部
You're only able to access what you've imported after this statement so,
你只能在导入语句之后访问所导入的内容
it's just less confusing to have these written first.
因此首先添加这些导入语句不会让人困惑
It's also nice for readers to see what a script
并且使读者能够在阅读代码的剩余部分之前
depends on before reading the rest of the code.
先了解脚本依赖于哪些其他脚本
Let's start with a really simple example.
我们先从一个很简单的示例开始
Here, I have a Python file called other_script.py that just prints two plus three.
这是一个叫做 other_script.py 的 Python 文件 它会输出 2+3
In this file demo.py,
我在这个 demo.py 文件中
I import other_script and then print four.
导入了 other_script 然后输出 4
When we run demo.py,
当我们运行 demo.py 时
this import statement tells Python to run code from that file which prints five.
这个导入语句告诉 Python 运行该文件中的代码 该文件会输出 5
It then continues to execute the rest of the code in this file printing four.
然后继续执行该文件中的剩余代码 并输出 4
If instead this file had the line num equals two plus three,
如果这个文件的代码是 num = 2 + 3
and we try to access this in demo.py,
我们尝试在 demo.py 中访问该文件
referencing it with just the name of the variable would return an error.
直接用变量名引用它将返回错误
To access objects in other_script.py,
要访问 other_script.py 中的对象
we need to use the name of the file followed by a dot,
我们需要输入文件名 然后是点
followed by the object to tell Python to look
接着是要访问的对象
for this object in the other_script file we imported.
告诉 Python 在导入的 other_script 文件中查找该对象
Now, it accesses the variables successfully.
现在成功地访问了该变量
When Python runs the script.
当 Python 运行该脚本时
It only has direct access to objects defined in the script.
它只能直接访问在该脚本中定义的对象
One of these objects is a module called other_script.
其中一个对象是一个叫做 other_script 的模块
A module is just a file with Python definitions and statements.
模块是具有 Python 定义和语句的文件
When we import a Python file like this,
当我们像这样导入 Python 文件时
it creates an object called other_script with a type module.
它会创建一个叫做 other_script 的对象 类型是模块
Let's see a more useful example of importing a module.
我们来看一个导入模块的更有用示例
Here, we have a Python file that contains useful functions we would like to use.
这是一个包含实用函数的 Python 文件 我们将使用这些函数
One, that returns the mean of a list and one that adds five to each element of a list.
其中一个函数返回列表的均值 另一个使列表中的每个元素加 5
We can import them into demo.py,
我们可以将这些函数导入 demo.py
and type useful_functions dot the name of the function to use them.
输入 useful_functions. 然后是要使用的函数的名称
You can imagine this would be very helpful if
可以想象 如果我们有很多在不同文件中经常使用的函数
we had many functions used a lot in different files.
这样操作的话会很方便
Although, it seems a little annoying that we have to type out
但是 每次我们想要使用某个文件中的函数时
the whole name of the file each time we want to use a function from it.
都需要输入整个文件名 这样很麻烦
We can make this much simpler by adding an alias.
我们可以通过添加别名使这一切变得异常简单
Here, I made an alias for the useful_function module UF.
我将这个 useful_function 模块的别名设为 uf
Now, I can just type UF instead of the whole module name when calling functions from it.
现在 当我调用该文件中的函数时 我可以直接输入 uf 而不用输入整个模块名
This is useful when we have objects we want
当我们有要从其他 Python 脚本中导入的对象（例如函数）时
to import from other Python scripts like functions.
这样会很方便
But, what if that script also includes
但是如果该脚本除了包含函数定义之外
executable statements in addition to function definitions that we don't want to import.
还包含我们不希望导入的可执行语句呢
For example, what if useful_functions.py has code
例如 如果 useful_functions.py 在脚本底部
at the bottom of the script that tests its functions and prints the results?
具有测试函数并输出结果的代码呢
This code is nice if we run useful_functions.py to test out these functions,
如果我们运行 useful_functions.py 以测试这些函数时 这段代码比较实用
but unnecessary if we're just trying to use these functions in another script.
但是如果我们只是尝试在另一个脚本中使用这些函数 则没必要运行这段代码
Here is where we can use this statement if name equals main.
我们可以使用语句“if __name__ == ‘__main__’”
By including these executable statements inside this if main block,
通过在这个 if name 块中包含这些可执行语句
we tell Python to execute this code only when
我们告诉 Python 仅当被执行的主程序
the main program being executed is this useful_functions.py.
是这个 useful_functions.py 时才执行这段代码
If we run this file the code inside this block is run.
如果我们运行这个文件 这个块中的代码将运行
However, if we run another script that simply imports
但是 如果我们运行另一个
useful_function.py this code is not run.
只是导入 useful_function.py 的脚本 这段代码不会运行
Generally, it's good practice to write executable statements inside
通常建议在 if name 块中编写可执行语句
an if name block or alternatively include them
或者将这些语句包含在函数 Main 中
in a function called Main and call this in the if name block.
并在 if name 块中调用该函数
You're probably wondering what this Name and Main stuff is.
你可能会疑问 __name__ 和 __main__ 是什么
Whenever we run a script like this,
每当我们像这样运行脚本时
Python actually sets a special built in variable called
Python 实际上会为任何模块设置一个特殊的内置变量
Name with two underscores before and after it for any module.
叫做 __name__ 前后都有两个下划线
Here, since we ran Python demo.py,
在此处 因为我们运行的是 Python demo.py
Python recognizes this module as the main program
Python 发现它是主程序
and sets the name variable for this module to the string Main.
并将该模块的 __name__ 变量设为字符串 __main__
For any modules that are imported in the script,
对于该脚本导入的任何模块
this built-in name variable is just set to the name of that module.
这个内置 __name__ 变量会设为该模块的名称